Hello

I'm Taylor Barron

Phone: (513) 876-5431

Email: taylor.barron989@gmail.com Website: See my skills here! Github: github.com/taylor-barron

About

Detail-focused front end developer with significant experience making beautiful, high functioning web applications. Specializes in Javascript, React, and CSS. Professional strengths include finding solutions to the difficult problems, collaboration, and being a self starter. Pairs excellent technical skills with excellent soft skills from 4+ years as a personnel manager for small businesses prior to tech career.

Skills

Top Skills: React, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Responsive Design, SQL, MySQL, Mongodb, Auth0, Bootstrap, Git, Github, Cloud Computing, Heroku

Skilled With: Java, Python, PHP, Node.js, OOP, AWS, Linux

Experience

May 2020 - Current

Malibu Jack's - Web Developer

- Developing web application from scratch
- Utilized SEO to increase page views by 30% translating into increased revenue

January 2022 - May 2022

KCTCS - Embedded Tutor

- Gave private and group tutoring sessions and reviews to Python and Java students
- Created study materials used by the college class

Personal Projects

Quick List - Cloud based live grocery list app - <u>Live Demo</u>

- Tech Stack: React front end, AuthO authentication/authorization, NodeJS backend hosted on Heroku, mongodb to store user data
- Uses a login system with persistent individual user data with clean, responsive design
- Uses functional programming and makes great use of hooks to organize items into editable categories or "purchased section"

Football Game Ranker - Ranks live football games to tell you the best games to watch - <u>Github Repo</u>

- Tech Stack: React front end hosted on Vercel, AuthO authentication/authorization, NodeJS backend hosted on Heroku, mongodb to store user data, Python server to get and structure live data hosted locally
- Without giving away anything about the game allows users to see which games they should watch from each time slot based on my football game ranking algorithm.
- Scrapes data from NCAA site and an API to feed algorithm. Results are stored in mongodb cluster to be retrieved by NodeJS server to serve to front end

• Users can adjust how important aspects of the graded games are important to them and receive custom games ranking. Example: Big plays or high talent levels on the teams.

Education

September 2020 - May 2022

KCTCS, Lexington, KY - AAS & Programming Certification

- Graduated with distinction
- 3.5 GPA
- Received A letter grade in every programming class